本字幕由大家字幕組原創翻譯制作僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為若因私自散布傳播造成法律問題 本字幕組概不負責更多影視請搜索并關注新浪微博  大家字幕組
翻譯： 忙著收紅包沒時間校對的肉 鑫鑫美少女 Cindy
翻譯： 漢謨拉 娃娃HJY 水水兒
時間軸&特效：Charybdis爪爪  靖芋芋  壓制：太陽雨  Sophy 校對：忙著收紅包沒時間校對的肉
狼·廳
第1季 第5集
公元1535年 《至尊法案》宣布亨利八世
為英格蘭教區首腦 但神圣羅馬皇帝及其大使
尤斯塔斯 沙皮既不承認亨利的頭銜
也不承認他與安妮 博林的婚姻關系
克倫威爾病愈后 為國王計劃了出巡路線
其中包括了造訪 簡 西摩 的家族
即  狼廳
約翰爵士
Sir John.
恭迎陛下
Your Majesty. Welcome.
我騎馬來的路上 遺失了帽子
I lost my hat, riding here.
永遠不會太遲的
It's never too late.
你應該再婚 再組建個新家庭
You should marry again, have another family.
說不定你在這兒就能找到個新娘呢
Perhaps you'll find a bride, while you're here with us.
弗朗西斯 威斯頓...
Francis Weston...
你應輕觸他一下
I believe your gentlemanly touch is required.
或者我們可以制造點兒噪聲
Perhaps we should make a noise,
讓他自然的醒來
to wake him naturally?
誰來笑兩聲
Someone laugh?
是啊 就這么做吧 湯姆
Yes, do that, Tom.
我并沒睡去
I wasn't asleep.
只是閉目養神而已
Just resting my eyes.
沒時間扭扭捏捏的
This is no time to be shy.
告訴克倫威爾 亨利問了你什么
Tell Cromwell what Henry asked you.
他問我 是否欣賞他
He asked me if I would look kindly on him.
譬如 他若是為我作詩
If he wrote me a poem, for instance.
我說我會的
I said I would.
很好
Good.
但如果他對你有什么別的企圖...
But if he attempts anything on your person...
..你就大叫
..scream.
要是沒人來呢
What if nobody comes?
別大叫
Don't scream.
祈禱...
Pray...
大聲的祈禱
out loud.
去嘗試喚醒陛下的虔誠之心
Something that will appeal to His Majesty's piety
和他的榮譽感
and sense of honour.
我會去翻翻我的禱告書的
I'll get my prayer book.
一定能找到些合適的語句
I'm sure I can find something that will fit the bill.
金博爾頓城堡
被流放的阿拉貢的凱瑟琳的宅邸
托馬斯 克倫威爾 國王的首席秘書大臣
Thomas Cromwell, Secretary to the King.
表明你的來意
Show your colours!
告訴他 放我們進去 別等我踢他屁股
Tell him to let us in, before I show his arse my boot.
好吧...
Well...
..我看起來怎樣
..how do I look?
這不就是他派你來的原因嗎
That's why he sent you, isn't it?
來看看我是不是真的快死了
To see if I really am dying?
他以前稱呼我為他的小花兒
He used to call me his flower.
我的長子出生的時候 是冬天
When my first son was born, it was winter.
嚴寒時根本就沒有開花的植物
There were no blooms to be had.
但他卻送了我七十二朵玫瑰...
He gave me six dozen roses...
用最純白的絲綢包裹著
..made of the purest white silk.
這么多年 我把它們都送給那些曾服侍過我的人了
Over the years, I have given them to those who have done me some service.
你...
Will...
你能讓瑪麗公主來看看我嗎
Will you let the Princess Mary visit me?
這不會對國王有什么傷害的
What harm can it do the King?
沙皮給瑪麗夫人寫了封信
Chapuys has written to the lady Mary,
說他能把她帶出這個國家
saying that he can get her out of the country.
不可能的
Never!
我用我的生命保證
I answer for it with my life.
亨利在想什么呢
What does Henry imagine?
他覺得瑪麗會帶著一支軍隊回來
Mary, returning with an army,
把他從王位上趕下來嗎
turning him out of his Kingdom?
真是可笑
It's laughable.
我可以親身為她的言行意向做擔保
I answer for her intentions with my own person.
那你要做的事可多了 夫人
Your own person has a lot to do, madam -
保證這個 擔保那個
guaranteeing this, answering for that.
但您卻只可死一次的
You can only die once.
當那時刻來臨時...
And when I do...
..我將會為亨利作出榜樣的
..I will set Henry an example,
如何對待自己的死期
for when his own time comes.
你經常想到國王之死嗎
Do you think about the King's death a lot?
我考慮的是他的余生
I think about his afterlife.
那個博林家的女孩怎么樣了
How is Boleyn's daughter?
她的孩子流掉了 我聽說
She lost the child, I am told.
我知道那是什么樣的感覺
I know how that is.
她和國王希望很快之后 再得一子
She and the King have hopes of another child, soon.
是已經有了希望
Particular hope,
還是將來會有點希望
or general hope?
我一直都很信任你的
My thoughts always confided in you.
也希望我們之間不要有嫌隙
I do hope there is no rift.
怎樣 她有了嗎
Well? Is she?
她還是什么都沒說
She's said nothing, still?
當然了 這女人聰明 什么都不會多言的
Of course, the wise woman says nothing
除非她真的能感受到胎動
until she feels the quickening.
有了
Yes.
她之前一直弄錯了...
She's been wrong before...
..不過 終于有了
..but, yes.
國王知道了嗎
Does the King know?
你該去告訴他 他說不準會當場授予你爵位的
You should tell him. He might knight you on the spot.
我覺得很有希望
I suppose it's to be expected.
她差不多整個夏天都和國王在一起
She was with the King for much of the summer
并且他不在她身邊時 還會寫情書給她
and when he wasn't with her, he would write her love letters
由哈里 諾里斯親手送達
and sent them by the hand of Harry Norris.
夫人 我得告辭了
My lady, I must leave you.
你之前可都是善于傾聽的人
And you were usually such a good listener.
窗子開著
The window was open.
它是那么的純真無辜
He was such an innocent...
什么樣的禽獸會做這種事
What kind of monster would do such a thing?
也許它不知怎的自己爬上了窗臺
Perhaps he got up on the ledge somehow and...
然后爪子打滑了
then his paws slipped.
- 爪子打滑 你說它爪子打滑    - 走開 瑪麗
- Paws slipped? Paws slipped? - Oh, get away, Mary!
哦 沒錯
Oh, yes -
我又給她重新受洗取名了
I've re-baptised my fool.
說起來...
Well...
國王的女兒差不多是個侏儒 是吧
the King's daughter is almost a dwarf, isn't she?
法國人看見她 會震驚的
The French will have a shock if they ever see her.
- 他們肯定會震驚的  - 沒錯
- They'll have a shock.- Yes.
我知道他們正試圖讓她與法國王子聯姻
I know they're trying for a match between her and the Dauphin.
而我自己的女兒...
While my own daughter...
我說過 讓你到法國去 商談一下她的聯姻之事
I told you to go to France and negotiate her marriage.
- 你卻說自己病了... - 我確實病了
- But you said you were ill...- I was ill.
你從未生過病
You're never ill
除非你在撒謊
unless you want to be.
如今法國人都在背后笑話我
And now the French laugh behind my back.
法國人壓根就不想聯姻
The French never intended a match.
我這女兒的出生簡直就是毫無意義的
It's as if my daughter had never been born.
就好像凱瑟琳還依舊是王后
As if Katherine was still Queen.
就好像我根本不存在
As if I didn't exist.
我不會允許瑪麗與王室聯姻的
I won't let them make a royal match for Mary.
我要你去見見她
I want you to visit her.
帶一個你家的帥小伙一同去
Take one of your handsome young men with you.
她這輩子從沒受過什么贊譽
She's never had a compliment in her life -
勾搭引誘她不會是什么難事
it shouldn't be hard to seduce her.
您希望她被破了處子身嗎
You want me to compromise her?
你要是想 自己上也可以
Do it yourself, if you want.
我聽說她很鐘意你的
I heard she liked you.
反正我只要她在大庭廣眾之下出丑
All that's needed is for her to make a fool of herself in public,
讓她名聲掃地
so she loses her reputation.
不行
No.
不行 你竟然說不行
No? No?
你說什么
What?
那不是我的目標
That's not my aim.
我也不會用那些手段的
Those are not my methods.
我知道你和西摩家關系甚密
I know you're talking to the Seymours.
你以為這是個秘密
You think it's a secret,
但我卻是無所不知的
but nothing is secret from me.
真是難以置信 你竟然把賭注全都壓在她身上
I can't believe you'd put your money on such a bad risk.
夫人 有段時間內 您也對我言聽計從
There was a time, madam, that you would listen to my advice.
現在讓我再給您點建議好嗎
Let me advise you now.
放棄你的所有計劃與圖謀吧
Drop your plans and schemes.
放下所有的包袱與負擔吧
Put down the burden of them.
低調行事做人 直到您的孩子出生
Keep yourself in quietness, until your child is born.
而簡呢
For Jane...
她不過是個分心的瑣事而已
..she's a distraction, that's all.
任她自生自滅去吧
Let it run its course.
- 假裝您從未見過她  - 他永不會棄我于不顧
- Pretend that you don't even see her... - He'll never abandon me.
永遠不會的
Never.
從我的加冕禮之后 英格蘭就進入了嶄新的時代
Since my coronation, there is a new England
我不在的話 這個國家舉步維艱
and it can't subsist without me.
我警告你...
I'm warning you...
在我的孩子出生前 克倫威爾
..make terms with me, Cremuel...
你最好和我達成共識
..before my child is born.
我聽說你要把所有的修女和修道士都趕出去
I hear you're going to put all the nuns and monks out on the road.
沙皮先生
Monsieur Chapuys,
無論我的屬下們去哪
wherever my commissioners go,
都會有一大幫修道士和修女們圍著他們 乞求寬恕
they meet monks and nuns who come to them, begging for their liberty -
聽到那些丑聞之后 我一點都不吃驚
and after the scandals I've heard, I'm not surprised.
修道士們將吃剩下的腐肉賣給窮人
Monks selling broken meats from the Last Supper to the poor.
年輕的信徒被年長的修道士們造訪到了床上去
Young novices being visited in their beds by older monks.
他們聲稱自己是"神圣使徒"
They claim they're living the "vita apostolica",
但你找到的卻全都是
but you didn't find the apostles
互摸私處的信徒 對吧
feeling each other's bollocks, did you?
去告訴你的主人 好的宗教應導人向善 而不是退化成獸性
Tell your master I mean good religion to increase, not wither.
我不會向主人撒謊 我只是稟實相告
I won't tell my master lies, if I tell him what I see.
我看到的是不滿
I see discontent.
我看到嚴寒未過 饑荒四起
I see famine, before the spring.
你們從帝國的領土上購買玉米
You're buying corn from the territories of the Emperor.
這些交易可是會被禁止的
This trade could be stopped.
把我國的民眾餓死了 對你的主人又有什么好處呢
What could your master possibly gain, by starving my countrymen?
他能看到 這些愚昧的民眾是怎樣被殘酷統治的
He would gain this - he would see how evilly they are governed!
亨利從藐視譏笑教皇開始
Henry begins by mocking the Pope
終將一天會投身
he will end up embracing...
惡魔的懷抱
..the devil.
尤斯塔斯
Eustache...
到底發生了什么
..what's happened?
你這是怎么了
What is this?
金博爾頓城堡傳來了消息
I have news from Kimbolton.
凱瑟琳王后她...
Queen Katherine...
她還剩一兩天的命了 我不想她...
She has only one or two days to live and I don't want her to...
托馬斯 我不想她孤獨死去
Thomas, I don't want her to die alone,
竟無愛她之人在側
without anyone who loves her.
恐怕國王也不會允許我去看她
And I'm afraid the King won't let me go.
那你會讓我去嗎
Will you let me go?
沙皮大使的拜訪探望
It would be a kindness
是對她的極大恩寵仁慈
to let her have a visit from Ambassador Chapuys.
為什么
Why?
這樣他就能更方便的和她密謀了嗎
So he can intrigue with her more conveniently?
夫人 她的醫生說 她已時日無多了
Her doctors suggest, Madam, that she will very soon be in her grave.
她就算死了 也會裹著尸布飛出來的
She'd fly out of it, shroud flapping,
來給我找找晦氣
if she thought she could cause me trouble.
陛下 羅馬皇帝也許是一個孝順的侄子
Your Majesty, the Emperor may be a fond nephew,
但他卻不會為了死去的女人和您永遠僵持的
but he won't keep up the quarrel for a dead woman.
這樣和解 對雙方都有好處 免除戰爭 進入和平新世紀
This could mean the end to the threat of war - a new era.
沙皮大使...
Ambassador Chapuys...
他從未承認過我的妻子是王后
has never acknowledged my wife as Queen.
除非他當眾拜見王后
Until he is prepared to bow before her, publicly,
否則我是不會接見他的
there will be no diplomacy with that man.
她終于是死了 感謝上帝
At last, God!
早就該死了
Not before time!
她可是非常想要見到她的弟弟呢
She's very much looking forward to seeing her younger brother
是不是啊 小寶貝
aren't you, dumpling?
我也和她一樣的迫切
And I share her impatience.
我也已經等了好久了
It has been a long enough wait.
我想全國民眾都要為她哀悼
I suppose we must expect the country to mourn for her.
她畢竟也曾是王后之尊
She was once given the title of "Queen".
她是錯誤的當上王后的
Mistakenly.
陛下
Majesty,
您是否要下令將尸體運送到圣保羅大教堂
do you wish the body brought to St Paul's?
將她安葬在彼得伯勒吧
We will lay her to rest in Peterborough.
那樣花費少點
It will cost less.
她給我寄了一封信
She sent me a letter.
我不想看
I don't want it.
你處理掉 好嗎
Get rid of it, will you?
理查德 里奇說國王想收回凱瑟琳的餐具和皮革品
Richard Rich says the King wants Katherine's plate and furs.
里奇說 如果她從未成為過他的妻子
Rich had to point out that if she was never, in fact, his wife,
那他無權收回她的遺產
he has no right to her property.
噢 他會收回那些皮革的
Oh, he'll have the furs.
"我將我們的女兒瑪麗鄭重托付給你
"I commend unto you our daughter, Mary...
希望你能擔當起父親的責任
..beseeching you to be a good father to her...
最后
..and lastly,
我在此立誓
I make this vow...
我在天堂之上 也會一直注視著你的作為"
..that mine eyes desire you, above all things."
要是我在你身旁
If I'd been with you,
我一定不會讓你遇到危險的
I could have put you out of danger.
我會用毛毯馬上撲滅這火的
I'd have beat it with a... with a blanket.
謝天謝地 你...
Oh, thank goodness that you...
要是我在就好了...
If I'd been here...
別弄了
Leave it!
別緊張 我的丈夫
Peace, my husband,
我沒有受傷
I am not harmed.
夫人
My Lady.
讓我先喝點東西
Let me drink this.
“有預言說...”
“...會有個英國王后被火燒死”
“...但我沒想到 ”
“...會是在王后自己的床上 ”
“...火源是一根不起眼的蠟燭 ”
“...不然就是有人故意這樣的 ”
“這蠟燭怎么會無人看管的呢？ ”
這帷幔本來是很好的...
This was a good piece...
怎么了
Yes, what is it?
手邊一定要備著水
Water must be kept at hand
每個時段都要讓女仆輪番服侍
and a woman appoin ted on every rota,
保證所有的燈都徹底熄滅
to check that all the lights are being extinguished.
無法想象這件事是怎么發生的
I can't imagine how this could have happened.
第一 這是內廷事務 不在你職權管轄范圍內
First, this is a household matter and not within your remit.
第二 她安然無恙
Second, she was in no danger.
第三 我不知道誰點的那只蠟燭
Third, I don't know who lit the candle.
第四 就算是我干的 我也不會告訴你
Four, if I did, I wouldn't tell you.
第五 沒有人會告訴你是誰干的
Five, no-one will tell you either.
如果 如果發生了
If, as it may happen,
某些人在熄燭之后 還潛入拜訪了王后...
some person visits the Queen after the lights are out...
..那可是件我們要遮掩嚴密的大事了
..then it is an event over which we should draw a veil.
某些人
Some person?
某些人 是為縱火而來的
Some person, for the purposes of arson?
或是另有目的
Or the purposes of something else?
羅奇福德夫人...
Lady Rochford...
簡 等你放下你的良心包袱的時候
Jane, when the time comes to unburden your conscience,
不要去找牧師
don't go to a priest.
他只會讓你懺悔
He'll give you penance.
而我卻會給你回報
I'll give you a reward.
里彭的貴族帶了多少錢貢獻給大主教
How much does the lordship of Ripon bring in to the Archbishop?
260英鎊多一點 陛下
A little over £260, sir.
索斯威爾呢
How much does Southwell bring in?
不到150英鎊
A scant £150.
我以為會更多點呢
Ha? I thought it would be more.
殿下...
Majesty...
..今天的比武上
..in the tournament, today?
如果您和我的兒子 格雷戈里 比試的話
If you should run against my son, Gregory,
您會控制自己不把他摔下馬去嗎...
will you forbear to unhorse him...
..如果能忍住的話
..if you can help it?
我們做事常常都是情不自禁的 對吧
We can't help what we do, really.
當你對一個人雷霆出手的時候 你無法控制
When you're thundering down at a man, you can't check.
真是一件罕見的事 你知道嗎 克倫
It's a very rare event, you know, Crom...
..打倒敵手的時候
..to bring down your opponent.
如果你是擔心他的表現 就大可不必了
If you're concerned about what showing he'll make, you needn't be.
他很有能力
He's very able.
我不在意他的表現
I don't really mind what showing he makes.
我只是不想讓他...
I just don't want him to be...
受到打擊
flattened.
你不來看比武了
You can't come.
拉夫回來了
Rafe is back.
我要和他談談他正在調查的修道院
I have to talk to him about some abbeys he's been surveying.
還有些文件要處理...
And there's my papers...
理查德會在這的 代表我
Richard will be here, to represent me.
這是我第一次比武
It's my first joust.
梵蒂岡給了亨利三個月的時間再度歸服
The Vatican has given Henry three months to return to obedience,
否則將他逐出教會的聲明
or the bull of excommunication against him
將會傳遍歐洲
will be distributed through Europe.
羅馬皇帝的艦隊已經出發前往阿爾及爾
The Emperor's fleet is set for Algiers
率領四萬全副武裝的士兵
with 40,000 armed men.
方坦的修道院長
The Abbot of Fountains
一直在按計劃的清洗自己的財產
has been systematically robbing his own treasury,
議會還有兩周就要舉行了
parliament opens in a fortnight.
國王說你是我們家族里的榮耀
The King says you're a credit to my house.
你也當之無愧
And you are.
好幾年前 還在你出生之前
Some years ago, before you were born,
我在威尼斯遇到了一位葡萄牙老騎士
I met an old Portuguese knight in Venice - one of those men
他是專門在歐洲以騎馬比賽為生的人
who made a career of riding to tournaments, throughout Europe.
我不知道...不知道那話什么意思...
I don't know... For what it's worth...
但他說比武的秘訣就是在你要輕輕松松的坐在馬鞍上
He said the secret to jousting was to sit easily in your saddle,
就像是出門呼吸新鮮空氣一般
like you're going out to take some air.
矛不要握的太緊 直到最后一刻在狠狠抓緊
Carry your lance loose, until the very last moment
最為重要的是...
and above all else...
..戰勝你的求生保命的本能...
..defeat your instincts to...
..去戰斗
..survive.
很好 我想你已經準備好了
Well, you're ready.
你看上去很棒
You look good.
謝謝你
Thank you.
禮物
Present.
你猜一下是什么
You have to guess.
圣阿波洛尼亞的牙嗎
St Appollonia's teeth?
不是
No.
從抹大拉的瑪麗亞的墓里挖出的牙齒
Teeth from the comb of Mary Magdalene?
是圣愛德蒙德的指甲碎屑
St Edmund's nail parings.
將它和其余的指甲們放在一起吧
Tip them in with the rest.
這個人肯定是有幾百個手指頭了
The man must have had 500 fingers.
還有什么事
What else?
之前梅登 布拉德利聲稱她有羅馬的許可
The prior at Maiden Bradley claims he has a licence, under papal seal,
允許他招妓
allowing him to keep a whore.
威斯敏斯特大教堂買了一頭大象的遺骨
Westminster Abbey bought the bones of a dead elephant.
現在告訴我他們想...
Now, tell me what they wanted with...
格雷戈里出事了嗎
Gregory?
不 是國王 是亨利
It's the King, it's... it's Henry.
他死了
He's dead.
比武還沒有開始
The tournament hadn't begun.
國王正騎馬跑向那個環 結果馬突然倒下了
The King was running towards the ring and the horse just went down.
他當時身邊沒有一個人 所以也沒有人能受到責備
No-one was near him, no-one to blame.
學士 如果這是真的...
Master, if this is true...
如果他死了...
If he is dead...
我們現在要在他們封堵港口之前逃跑嗎
Should we escape now, before they block the ports?
找菲茲威廉來
Fetch Fitzwilliam.
讓開 讓開
Move, move!
Move! Move!
- 把鏡子照照他嘴唇  - 已經試過了
- Fetch a mirror to his lips. - It was tried.
那你什么意思 就讓他躺在這里
What do you mean, leaving him lying here,
不得基督的觸碰
untouched by Christian hands?!
上帝啊 克倫威爾 - 你死定了
By God, Cromwell - you're a dead man!
諾爾福克大人 諾爾福克大人 王后在哪
My Lord Norfolk, My Lord Norfolk! Where is the Queen?
在看臺上
On the floor.
我已經親自告訴她了
I told her myself.
我的分內之事
My place to do it.
她警告你要聽話的
She warned you to be obedient.
現在她要攝政 你的好日子到頭了
And now she's Regent, your days are finished!
胡說八道
No, no, no!
沒人會讓一個大肚子女人攝政掌權的
No woman with big belly as Regent.
我才應該掌權
Me! Me!
- 格雷戈里 - 財政大臣帶來了
- Gregory!  - We've brought the Master Treasurer.
謝謝你 謝謝
Thank you, thank you.
瑪麗公主 如果她落入博林的手中 她必死無疑
The Princess Mary - if she falls into Boleyn hands, she's dead.
我們得在消息擴散前 快回城去
We have to get up-country before this news does.
快 菲茲威廉 快走
Go, Fitzwilliam. Go quickly.
瑪麗受博林家的人監護 如果他們不放人怎么辦
Mary's keepers are Boleyns. What if they won't yield her?
那她必死無疑
Well, then she's dead.
但如果我們讓她落到天主教徒的手上
We let her fall into the hands of the papists,
他們會擁護她為女王 我也會死
they'll set her up as Queen - and I'm dead.
還會爆發內戰
There'll be civil war.
我不清楚...
I don't know...
女人不能攝政 克倫威爾 女人不可以掌權的
A woman cannot rule, Cromwell! A woman cannot rule!
噢 天吶 我的天
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
陛下有呼吸了 陛下有呼吸了
The King's breathing, the King's breathing!
陛下萬壽無疆
Long live the King!
挺住 加油
Come on, come on.
挺住 挺住
挺住...醒了 醒了
Come on... There you are, there you are!
你挺過來了 你能看得見我嗎 太好了 沒事了
There you are! Do you see me? That's it, that's it.
散開 退開點 讓他喘口氣
Get back, move away. Let him breathe!
讓他呼吸 讓他呼吸
Let him breathe, let him breathe.
有多少人能說
How many men can say,
"我唯一的摯友是英格蘭的國王"
"My only friend is the King of England?"
你可能認為我擁有一切...
You'd think I have everything...
但如果亨利死了...
..but take Henry away...
我不知道 克倫
I don't know, Crom.
你不是孤立無助的 知道嗎
You're not without support, you know?
原諒我有所質疑
Forgive my scepticism.
我是說 如果你需要支持...
I mean, you would have support...
只要對抗博林家族 就能得到支持
..should you need it, against the Boleyns.
可我為什么要支持呢
Well, why should I need that?
畢竟王后和我是完美搭檔
The Queen and I are perfect friends.
原諒我有所質疑
Forgive my scepticism.
這種支持...
This support...?
尼古拉斯 克洛爵士說...
Sir Nicholas Carew says he thinks...
他覺得你是個很容易相處的人
you're an easy fellow to get on with.
是嗎
Does he?
也許...
Perhaps...
也許你可以和他一起進餐
Perhaps you should dine with him?
克倫 如果陛下沒能醒來...
What would have happened, Crom...
會發生什么
if the king had not recovered?
安妮會不擇手段奪取大權
Anne would have all, to rule herself.
盡管她和她的叔夫諾爾福克爭執一番
Though she'd have a fight with her Uncle Norfolk.
他們兩方 我到底該支持誰呢
Between the two of them, which one would I back?
我覺得應該支持夫人
The lady, I think.
讓安妮夫人攝政
Let the lady be Regent
那么博林家族就會背棄我們
and the Boleyns will walk on our backs.
你的頭會被掛在長釘上
And your head will be on a spike.
但當然 如果她能為國王誕下王子的話
But of course, that will come to pass anyway...
那這一切終將發生
if she gives Henry a son.
陛下
My Lord...
我懇求您
I pray
全英格蘭都懇求您
the whole of England prays
不要再參與馬上比武了
that you will never joust again.
你騎在我上面的時候 怎么不干脆閹了我
Why not geld me, while you're at it?
那樣你就順心多了吧 女士
That would suit you, wouldn't it, madam?
孩子看起來像是男嬰
The child had the appearance of a male
大概在孕期15周
and of about 15 weeks' gestation.
什么叫 "看起來像是男嬰"
What do you mean, "the appearance of?"
我只是重復醫生的話...
I only repeat the words of the doctor...
滾開點 臭娘們 你又沒生過
Oh, get away with you, woman! You've never given birth.
你懂什么
What do you know?
她的床畔本該有侍女守著的
There should've been a matron at her bedside -
但是人呢
but oh, no
一有災禍降臨 你們博林家的人就蜂擁而至
you Boleyns must all crowd in, whenever disaster strikes.
看來上天不會賜予我小王子
I see that God will not give me male children.
如果一個國王沒有嫡子傳承...
If a king cannot have a son...
如果他不能給國家帶來穩定
If he cannot give stability to his realm...
那無論他做的任何事都毫無意義了
..then it doesn't matter what else he can do.
戰爭之勝利...
The victories...
法令之公正...
the just laws...
法庭之著名...
..the famous courts...
什么都無用
..nothing.
在我看來...
It seems to me...
好像是我自己不清不楚的就促成了這段婚姻
that I was dishonestly led into this marriage.
怎么叫不清不楚...
How...dishonestly?
我感覺像是被引誘了一般...
It seems to me I was seduced...
或許是...
..practised upon...
或許是魅力嗎
..perhaps with charms?
用魔咒什么的 女人就是會做這樣的事的
With spells? Women do such things.
要是果真如此的話
And if that were so...
這段婚姻應該無效的 對嗎
..the marriage would be null, wouldn't it?
"國王 送給她一個錢袋
"He sent her a purse - the King.
天知道里面裝了多少錢"
Christ knows how much was in it."
她作何反應
What did she do?
她送還回去了
She sent it back.
隨錢包一起送的信呢
And the letter he sent with it?
她沒有打開
She didn't open it.
但是退還前...
But before she returned it...
她吻了一下信上的火漆印
She kissed the seal.
吻了它
Kissed it!
她可真是聰明啊
What genius possessed her?
如今亨利四處談論 "善良賢惠的簡"
Now Henry's walking around, talking about "the virtuous and chaste Jane".
對此你怎么看
What do you say to that?
局勢變了 克倫威爾
The game's changed, Cromwell.
既然安妮又一次流產
Now that Anne has failed again,
亨利很可能會再婚
it's possible that Henry may wish to remarry.
只要陛下還與現任王后保持婚姻關系
As long as the King holds by the present Queen,
我也一樣會站在她這邊
I will hold by her, too.
那你就沒考慮過自己的利益嗎
So you have no interest of your own in this?
我代表國王的利益
I represent the King's interests.
那是我存在的意義
That's what I'm for.
主教大人
My Lord Bishop,
我聽說你要動身去法國了
I hear you're leaving us for France?
我們會想念你的
We shall miss you.
我去了趟帕特尼...
I went down to Putney...
..或者準確地說 我派了個仆從去 知道了一些關于你的事情
..or to be accurate, I sent a servant. I learnt things about you.
你曾殺了一個人
You've killed a man.
又不是在你的轄區內
Not in this jurisdiction.
你可真是劣性不改 斯蒂芬
Do your worst, Stephen.
派你的人四處奔走
Put your men on the road,
花錢打探消息
lay out money,
搜查整個歐洲...
search Europe...
你只會發現我所有的技能才干 都是英格蘭所需要的
You'll not find any talent I possess that England cannot use.
那個在帕特尼被你砍的家伙 死了
That lad you knifed in Putney died.
辛虧你逃得早 克倫威爾
You did well to run, Cromwell.
那個家族給你下了圈套
The family had a noose for you.
你的父親...用錢打發了他們
Your father...bought them off.
什么
What?
你看看
You see?
我知道一些連你自己都不知道的事
I know things about your life you don't know yourself.
我打擾你了嗎
I am disturbing you?
尤斯塔斯
Eustache?
不 我剛剛只是在回憶
No, I was just remembering.
請坐下吧
Sit down.
紅衣主教大人過去常常告訴人們 我是一個孤兒...
The cardinal used to tell people that I was an orphan...
...或者說...
..or else that...
我不知道...我是愛爾蘭人
I don't know... I was Irish.
最近剛剛從監獄里逃出來
Recently escaped from prison.
他說對別人欺瞞你的過去 才是明智的
He said it was wise to deceive others about your past,
即使壓根沒什么可隱瞞的
even if there was nothing to conceal.
但是我在想...
But I was wondering...
是否有可能是在欺騙自己呢
whether it's possible to deceive oneself.
關于什么
About what?
你所信仰的你的人生
Something you believed about your life.
你是誰
Who you are...
是什么
What you are.
你參加了葬禮
You attended the funeral?
我拒絕去了
I refused to.
她并沒有以王后之尊下葬
She was not buried as a queen.
我聽說那個姘頭穿了一身黃衣來慶賀凱瑟琳的死
I hear the concubine wore yellow, to celebrate Katherine's death?
她認為原配逝去 她的地位就能得到改善
She thought her passing would change her position.
也許會變 但也可能不能如其所愿
So it may, but perhaps not in the way she thinks.
聽說有這么一個"西摩"的女孩
There is talk about this "Semer" girl.
我能見見她嗎
May I meet her?
我還以為你只是來陪我的
And here I thought you'd come just for my company.
你提到的這個女士叫"西摩"
The lady you refer to is called "Seymour" -
我很驚訝你竟然會對她感興趣
and I'm surprised you take such an interest.
我原本以為你可能更感興趣
I would have thought you were more interested
亨利要娶哪位法國的公主
in which French princess Henry will marry,
他是否該取消當下的安排呢
should he dissolve his current arrangements.
克倫威爾 你曾告訴我那只是個童話故事
Cremuel, you told me that was a fairy tale!
你曾自稱是我主人的朋友
You have expressed yourself a friend of my master.
別告訴我 你現在倒支持與法國的聯姻了嗎
Tell me you won't countenance a French match?
我可以影響亨利國王 尤斯塔斯...
I have influence on King Henry, Eustache...
..但我不會去控制他的
..but I do not claim to govern him.
為了和亨利相處 你就必須投其所好
To succeed with Henry, you have to anticipate his desires.
接著然后...
But then...
..如果他改變心意...
..if he changes his mind...
..你站出來...
..you stand out there...
...揭發他 不
..expose, no?
安娜才是你需要害怕的
It's Anne you should fear.
她是不顧一切的 很危險
She is desperate and dangerous.
先發制人 在她打壓你之前
Strike first, before she strikes you.
還記得她是怎么扳倒沃爾西的嗎
Remember how she brought down Wolsey.
也許你應該到宮廷中來做彌撒
Perhaps you should come to mass, at court?
克倫威爾!
Cromwell!
你早知道這種事會發生的
You knew this was going to happen.
回避她這么久
After all this time avoiding her,
一直不愿意承認她
avoiding having to acknowledge her...
這些事都將會傳到皇帝陛下那去
This will get back to the Emperor.
但愿他能理解吧
Let's hope he will understand.
必須要做個了結的 尤斯塔斯
It had to be done, Eustache.
為什么
Why?
王子并不像常人一般思考
Princes do not think as other men do.
如今你承認了他的第二次婚姻
Now you have acknowledged his second marriage.
現在只要他愿意
Now, if he likes...
..他會就這樣放手的
..he can let it go.
當博林家的人在他身邊時 可憐的家伙
When the Boleyns closed around him - poor fellow.
他看上去像是被奴隸商人拐走一樣
Looked as if he was being carried off by slavers.
他不知道他將在哪個國家醒過來
He didn't know what country he was going to wake up in.
我也不知道
No more do I.
我們去找別人聊聊吧 別管他們了
Let's go - find a crust to gnaw on somewhere - leave them to it.
克倫威爾
Cromwell?
我的主人 羅馬皇帝希望您能夠同意
My master the Emperor hopes you will look kindly
瑪麗公主與西班牙聯姻
on a Spanish match for Princess Mary.
你太自以為是了吧 沙皮
You presume too much, Chapuys!
別裝作你很了解我的原則 大使
Do not presume to know my policy, ambassador!
就像是所謂的討價還價 是嗎
So this was all a bargaining tool, was it?
- 陛下... - 你向我的妻子鞠躬 然后現在向我來討債了是嗎
- Your Majesty... - You bow to my wife, then you send me the bill?
我并沒有忘記 我是如何幫助你的主人對抗法國的
I have not forgotten how I helped your master against the French.
他承諾會給我封地
He promised me territory -
接下來我便得知 他竟然和弗朗索瓦一世簽訂了條約
next thing I hear, he's making a treaty with Francois!
皇帝視我為兒戲
The Emperor treats me like an infant!
先舍棄我 又討好我 然后又再次舍棄我
First he whips me, then he pets me, then he whips me again!
告訴他 我不是個無知幼嬰
Well, tell him I am not an infant!
告訴他 不要多管我的私家事
And tell him to keep out of my family business!
先是干涉我和誰結婚
First he tells me how I should marry,
現在又想干預我的女兒的婚姻
then he wants to show me how to deal with my own daughter!
我要求一個正式 公開的道歉
I demand a profound and public apology!
我不知道我應該為了什么而道歉
I don't know what I'm supposed to apologise for!
我是誠心誠意來這里
I come here in good faith,
卻要和那個禽獸面對面
I'm tricked into meeting that creature face to face -
然后還要被亨利辱罵
and then I'm attacked by Henry!
他想要我的主人 他需要我的主人
He wants my master, he needs my master -
可是他卻玩這樣的花招
and instead, he plays these games!
放松 冷靜
Peace, peace.
我們會去道歉的 讓他平靜下來
We will do the apologising. Let him cool down.
- 別緊張 我們會繼續商談下去的... - 克倫威爾
- Never fear, we can keep the talks going... - Cromwell!
我知道你做了什么
I know what you've done.
這件事情你做的太過火了
You have gone too far in this matter.
你對他保證了 是嗎
You've made him promises, haven't you?
你壓根沒有任何權利做保證
Well, you have no authority!
你將我的名譽置于險地
You have put my honour in jeopardy!
我在想些什么呢
What did I expect?
像你這樣的人 怎么會知道公主的名譽有多重要
What would a man like you know about the honour of princess?
你告訴他 你能把國王玩弄于股掌之間了嗎
You've told him you have the king in your pocket?
不要否認
Don't deny it!
你整天像教育自己的孩子一般教育我
You would train me up, like one of your boys -
讓我在你每早下樓是 握帽致禮
have me touch my cap when you come down in the morning
然后和你說 "早安 先生"
and say "How do you, sir?"
我現在還真的相信了
Well, I really believe
你覺得自己才是真正的國王
you think you are the King...
而我才是鐵匠之子
and I am the blacksmith's boy!
你說是嗎
Don't you?
是不是
愿上帝保佑陛下
God preserve Your Majesty.
現在...
And now...
恕我失陪...
will you excuse me?
交叉你的手腕
Cross your wrists.
像這樣
Like this.
浸在水里
Get it in the water.
保持交叉的姿勢
Keep your wrists crossed.
能減輕點疼痛
Confuses the pain.
我相信你已經得到了教訓
I trust a lesson has been learnt
你生來不是貴族
You are not a gentleman born.
你不該越權干涉你力不能及的事務
You should not meddle in affairs of those set above you.
陛下可能會想要見你
His Majesty may be pleased to bring you into his presence...
來吧 沃爾西 我們來接你進那個
Come, Wolsey! We're fetching you to Hell,
等你作餐的魔王們的地獄里去
where Beelzebub is expecting you to supper!
但你應當永遠銘記
But you should always remember who it was
自己的地位 得之于誰
that placed you where he could see you.
從現在開始 請記住你是為誰而效忠
From now on, remember who you serve.
我從中 "受益匪淺"
I shall profit from this lesson...
我向你保證 先生
I assure you, sir.
那就看你表現
See you do.
所以...
And so...
陛下 如果您覺得滿意...
Majesty, if it please you...
懇求您慎重考慮一下...
Look favourably on the Emperor's overtures...
羅馬皇帝的提議
..we beg you.
為了國家和聯邦考慮一下
For the sake of the realm and the commonweal.
如果真是為了聯邦著想的話 我...
Well, if it's for the good of the commonweal, I...
那我確實應該和沙皮去談判協商
I shall begin negotiations with Chapuys.
我猜我得對身邊所有的人都忍辱屈尊才行
I suppose I must swallow any personal insults I have received.
其他的事先暫不考慮
Other topics will not be open for discussion.
羅馬皇帝同自己的議員們 談論了瑪麗的事
The Emperor has discussed Mary with his own councillors.
他希望她嫁給他的親戚
He'd like her married to his own relatives.
除非她的言行舉止讓我無法忍受
I will in no wise suffer her to leave this country,
否則我絕不讓她離開英國受苦
until her behaviour to me is as it should be.
于我而言...
Myself...
我提議在國內為她選婿
I'd go up-country -
但如果她不同意
and if she would not sign the oath,
那我會好好的教育她 直到她順從屈服
I'd beat her head against the wall, till it were soft as a baked apple.
多謝 諾爾福克閣下
Thank you for that, my Lord Norfolk.
她仍沉浸在她母親的去世之殤中
Her mother's death is still raw with her.
我相信她會在接下來的幾周里
I have no doubt that she will see her duty,
意識到自己肩負的責任
in these next weeks.
挺開心終于聽到你說話了 克倫威爾
How pleasing to hear from you at last, Cromwell.
我猜你今天的緘默
Are we to assume that this new-found reticence of yours
是與昨天的事有關
relates to yesterday's events?
如果我沒記錯的話
When His Majesty, if I do recall correctly,
就是陛下揭露你野心的那件事
administered a check to your ambition?
再次感謝 威爾特閣下
Thank you again, My Lord Wiltshire.
瑪麗不會遠嫁異國的
There will be no foreign match for Mary.
務須多言
That is final.
陪我走走可好
Will you walk with me?
希望有一天我們能去草原上走走
I wish we would go down to the weald one day -
跟技藝高超的鐵匠們聊聊
talk to the ironmasters.
我有很多圖紙 數理圖紙 還有很多建議規劃...
I've had various drawings - mathematical drawings and advices...
一起探討如何改進我們的武器裝備 但我...
..concerning how our ordnance can be improved, but I...
我不能...
I can't...
我無法做到像你一般出色
I can't make as much of it as you would.
因為...
It's because...
嗯...
Well...
因為你是我的左膀右臂 閣下
Because you are my right hand, sir.
那么 還要不要一起繼續走走
So, shall we go down?
就咱倆 一起去看看那些鍋爐可好
You and I, meet the charcoal burners?
當然
Of course.
但今夏就算了 陛下
But not this summer, sir.
我覺得你最近實在是太忙了
I think you will be too busy.
是啊
Yeah.
我不能再像以前那樣頹廢生活了 克倫威爾
I cannot live as I have lived, Cromwell.
你必須得幫我從安妮的魔爪中...
You must free me from this...
解脫出去
..from Anne.
可能她跟哈里 珀西...
Perhaps she and Harry Percy...
他倆關系好的就像夫妻一樣 不是么
They were good as married, weren't they?
如果那不能奏效的話 你知道我...
And if that won't run, you know I was...
我曾偶爾和安妮的姐姐 瑪麗 相處...
I was, on occasion, with Anne's sister, Mary?
可能走的確實是近了點...
Perhaps having been with kin so near...
不管怎樣...
Anyway...
我相信你的判斷力和能力
I trust in your discretion and your skill.
務必秘密行事
Be very secret.
西摩小姐的雙手可真是小巧玲瓏
Does not Mistress Seymour have the tiniest hands?
"她有沒有一雙小巧的手"
"Doesn't she have the tiniest hands?"
"她有沒有最白皙的脖頸"
"Does she not have the whitest throat?"
她有沒有最濕滑的陰道
Has she not the wettest cunt you've ever groped?
夠了夠了
That's enough.
周圍可是有克倫威爾的眼線耳目的
Cromwell's spy is about.
他們在非議王后
They talk about the Queen.
他們是誰
They?
威斯頓 布里頓
Weston, Brereton...
諾里斯也時不時插嘴
sometimes Norris.
繼續說
Go on.
王后需要盡快再懷上個孩子
The Queen needs to conceive another child, quickly.
可他們卻說 亨利他 "不行"
And they say that Henry cannot be trusted to do the deed, so...
他們得"幫幫"他
one of them has to step in and do him a favour.
他們討論出什么結論沒
Do they come to any conclusion?
他們只是說說而已的吧 不會做什么的
They wouldn't really do it - none of them. It's just talk.
那到底有沒有討論出結果
So do they come to any conclusion?
我覺得他們都是各執己詞的
I think it's every man for himself.
我相信你說得對
Well, I'm sure you're right.
聽起來像是說大話
Sounds like idle talk.
我想你聽的這些話都不一定能派上用場
I don't think it will be necessary to use this...
不過還是謝謝你 拉夫
..but thank you, Rafe.
問題關鍵是 托馬斯...
Trouble is, Thomas...
國王想另娶新歡
The King wants a new wife.
就給他再找一個吧
Fix him one.
我當初沒能如他愿
I didn't...
現在我就已經死了
..and now I'm dead.
彼以國士待我，我以國士待之，用過免費優質字幕服務，
而又有能力的人，有義務將這個免費服務做下去若有心加入我們 聯系：QQ群 428872140 更多影視請搜索并關注新浪微博 @大家字幕組